{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Water insoluble enzymes can be prepared by using multifunctional agents that are bifunctional in nature and have", "opta": "low molecular weight", "optb": "high molecular weight", "optc": "high equivalent weight", "optd": "low reactivity", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Functional groups of the nonessential amino acid residues that are suitable for the immobilization process are", "opta": "free \u03b1-, \u03b2- or \u03b3 carb oxyl groups", "optb": "\u03b1 or \u03b2 amino groups", "optc": "phenyl, hydroxyl, sulfhydryl or imidazole groups", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which medium is used for the production of Penicillin using immobilized cells", "opta": "1% peptone medium", "optb": "glucose medium", "optc": "Yeast extract medium", "optd": "LB broth", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is taken as an assumption in the distributed model?", "opta": "The reaction occurs at every position and the kinetics of the reaction are of the same form as observed for free enzyme.", "optb": "Mass transfer through the immobilized enzyme occurs via molecular diffusion", "optc": "There is no mass transfer limitation at the outside surface of the spherical immobilized enzyme", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The immobilized enzyme produced by micro encapsulation technique provides", "opta": "an extremely large surface area", "optb": "smaller surface area", "optc": "high amount of solvent", "optd": "relatively smaller surface area", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is considered as a disadvantage to the adsorption method of immobilization?", "opta": "It is possible to separate and purify the enzymes while being immobilized", "optb": "The enzymes are not usually deactivated by adsorption", "optc": "The adsorption is a reversible process", "optd": "State of immobilization is very sensitive to solution pH, ionic strength and temperature", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During the enzymatic reaction of an immobilized enzyme, the rate of substrate transfer is", "opta": "equal to that of substrate consumption", "optb": "more than that of substrate consumption", "optc": "lesser than that of substrate consumption", "optd": "is nothing to do with the substrate consumption", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The immobilized technique involving chemical method is", "opta": "covalent bond formation dependent", "optb": "non-covalent bond formation dependent", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "ionic bond formation dependent", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a steady state condition, the change of substrate concentration (dCs/dt) is", "opta": "zero", "optb": "1", "optc": ">1", "optd": "<1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Damkohler number(NDa) is", "opta": "the ratio of the maximum reaction rate to the maximum mass transfer rate", "optb": "the ratio of the minimum reaction rate to the maximum mass transfer rate", "optc": "the ratio of the maximum reaction rate to the minimum mass transfer rate", "optd": "the ratio of the minimum reaction rate to the minimum mass transfer rate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For glucose isomerization by immobilized enzyme, the reactor generally used is", "opta": "CSTR", "optb": "plug flow", "optc": "packed bed", "optd": "fluidized bed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If Damkohler number, NDa >>1, the reaction rate is much greater than the mass transfer rate and the overall reaction is controlled by the rate of mass transfer. In this case, the enzyme reaction can be described as (where Csb and Cs are the substrate concentration in bulk of solution and at the immobilized enzyme surface respectively. ks mass transfer coefficient, and a is the surface area of an immobilized enzyme particles)", "opta": "rp = ksa(Csb-Cs)", "optb": "rp = ksaCsb", "optc": "rp = ksaCs", "optd": "rp = ksa(Csb+Cs)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most commonly employed cross-linked polymer is the", "opta": "polyacrylamide gel", "optb": "collagen", "optc": "celluloses", "optd": "cation exchange resin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not the correct answer?", "opta": "Immobilized enzyme may show selectively altered chemical properties", "optb": "Immobilized enzyme may show selectively altered physical properties", "optc": "Immobilized enzyme may simulate the realistic natural environment where the enzyme come from the cell", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Commonly employed water insoluble supports for the covalent attachment of enzyme include", "opta": "acrylamide based polymers", "optb": "polypeptides", "optc": "dextran", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a physical method of immobilization?", "opta": "Adsorption", "optb": "Entrapment", "optc": "Micro encapsulation", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The support material for immobilization of cells of Bacillus subtilis is", "opta": "ion exchange resins", "optb": "gelatin", "optc": "Anthracite", "optd": "agarose and carbodiimide", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The intraparticle mass transfer resistance can affect the rate of enzyme reaction, if enzymes are immobilized by", "opta": "copolymerization or microencapsulation", "optb": "crosslinking using multifunctional reagents", "optc": "adsorption", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The covalent attachment of enzyme molecules is via", "opta": "nonessential amino acids residues to water insoluble, functional supports", "optb": "essential amino acids residues to water insoluble, functional supports", "optc": "nonessential amino acids residues to water soluble, functional supports", "optd": "essential amino acids residues to water soluble, functional supports", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To measure the extent to which the reaction rate is lowered because of resistance to mass transfer, the effectiveness factor of an immobilized enzyme, \u03b7 can be defined as", "opta": "reaction rate/rate if not slowed by diffusion", "optb": "rate if not slowed by diffusion/ reaction rate", "optc": "actual reaction rate/ rate if not slowed by diffusion", "optd": "rate if not slowed by diffusion/ actual reaction rate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not the method for producing immobilized enzymes with multifunctional reagents?", "opta": "Enzymes are adsorbed on the surface active support followed by intermolecular cross linking", "optb": "Functional groups are introduced on the support to react co-valently with enzymes", "optc": "Enzymes are cross linked intermolecularly", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The immobilization technique involving physical method is", "opta": "covalent bond formation dependent", "optb": "non-covalent bond formation dependent", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "ionic bond formation dependent", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the commonly employed adsorbents?", "opta": "Calcium carbonate", "optb": "Alumina", "optc": "Celluloses", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Various techniques are available for determining the effective diffusivity of solute in gel. Thin disk method uses", "opta": "a diffusion cell with two compartments divided by a thin gel", "optb": "a diffusion cell with two compartments", "optc": "a diffusion cell with two compartments plus by a thin gel", "optd": "a diffusion cell with two compartments multiply by a thin gel", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effectiveness factor increases with the", "opta": "increase of diffusivity and decreased with the increase of particle size", "optb": "increase of diffusivity and increased with the increase of particle size", "optc": "decrease of diffusivity and decreased with the increase of particle size", "optd": "increase of diffusivity and decrease with the decrease of particle size", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}